<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Citadel</title><link>https://shaswatgupta.github.io/tech/</link><description>Recent content on Citadel</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 20 Jul 2021 21:40:56 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://shaswatgupta.github.io/tech/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Who is this guy?</title><link>https://shaswatgupta.github.io/tech/about/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jul 2021 21:40:56 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://shaswatgupta.github.io/tech/about/</guid><description>I am Shaswat Gupta, a Senior Site Reliability Engineer at media.net.
2013-2017: B.Tech in Information Technology at NIT Durgapur.
2017-present: SRE profile at media.net.
Major Research Contributions
Author Profile on IEEE.
A semantic web and linked data based framework for Smart City data management S. Gupta, A. Padhy, A. Adhikari and A. Dutta, &amp;quot;A semantic web and linked data based framework for Smart City data management,&amp;quot; 2016 13th International Conference on Electrical Engineering/Electronics, Computer, Telecommunications and Information Technology (ECTI-CON), 2016, pp.</description></item><item><title>Macbook Pro setup</title><link>https://shaswatgupta.github.io/tech/blog/2021-01-30-macbook-pro-setup/</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 Jan 2021 15:29:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://shaswatgupta.github.io/tech/blog/2021-01-30-macbook-pro-setup/</guid><description>Last year around march i lost by Macbook to water. Here I am back again setting up my Macbook Pro 2019 model.
Guide to follow for first time Macbook setup: Open: https://sourabhbajaj.com/mac-setup/ on safari.
Install xcode and homebrew
sudo xcode-select --install /bin/bash -c &amp;quot;$(curl -fsSL https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Homebrew/install/master/install.sh)” Some of tools i use on day to day basis. brew install lastpass-cli vim git wget telnet stormssh tmuxinator telegram-cli go scala sbt openjdk@11 wireguard-tools wireguard-go gh hugo kubectx kube-ps1 helm nmap ipcalc jq youtube-dl ffmpeg luarocks Installations with cask.</description></item><item><title>Windows 10 Laptop setup with WSL 2.0.</title><link>https://shaswatgupta.github.io/tech/blog/2021-01-30-windows-10-laptop-setup-with-wsl-2.0./</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 Jan 2021 15:29:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://shaswatgupta.github.io/tech/blog/2021-01-30-windows-10-laptop-setup-with-wsl-2.0./</guid><description>Couple of days back i lost my Macbook to water and here i am shifting to windows in middle of a national wide lockdown. (Future me should remember this COVID19 lockdown of 2020)
I personally prefer Linux based machines but in middle of lockdown this is the best i can arrange to continue my office work. Lets give windows and wsl 2.0 a try instead of switching between a dual boot system that we used to have in our college days.</description></item><item><title>License</title><link>https://shaswatgupta.github.io/tech/license/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://shaswatgupta.github.io/tech/license/</guid><description>I want people to be able to use anything if they want to with attribution and without warranty. I think these licenses are appropriate. Please let me know if there are better licenses that achieve this goal.
Content License Except where otherwise noted, my non-code content on this website is licensed under a Creative Commons BY-NC 4.0(Creative Commons Attribution-Non Commercial 4.0).
Code License Except where otherwise noted, my code on this website is licensed under MIT:</description></item></channel></rss>